[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
So when we visualize data organized as a graph,
当我们将数据组成图来可视化时
we'll likely want to lay it out in a plane.
我们很可能想把它 摆放在一个平面上
There's a kind of graph that enables that called a planar graph.
有一种类型的图可以做到这点 它被称为平面图（planner graph）
So as we saw before we're going to represent data items as nodes and
如之前所看到的 我们要 将数据项表示为节点
edges between nodes will represent relationships between those data items.
而节点间的边将表示那些数据项间的关系
In some cases we'll have a graph, a planar graph for example.
在某些情况下 我们会用到一个图 例如一个平面图
A planar graph can be drawn such that the edges connecting the nodes don't cross.
可以这样画一个平面图 让连接节点边都不相交
That's called a planar embedding.
这被称为平面嵌入（planar embedding）
The same planar graph,
同样一个平面图
in this case you've got the same foreign nodes connected by the same five edges.
在这个例子中 同样的外部节点 由相同的5条边连接起来
In this non planar embedding the edges cross.
在这个非平面嵌入的例子中 这些边是相交的
And so, the same graph, they're both planar graphs.
所以 相同的图 它们两个都是平面图
What we'd like to do is be able to find the embedding,
我们希望做的是 能够找到这种嵌入
the way to lay out the nodes so that the edges don't cross, so
即排布那些节点的方式 使这些边不相交
it'll be clearer to the observer, the relationship between the nodes.
这样 对观察者来说 节点间的关系将会更清晰
So we can do this.
于是，我们可以这样做。
We can do this for very large graphs.
对于非常大的图 我们也可以这样做
For example, here's a triangle mesh representing a geometric object.
例如 有一个三角形网格 它表示了一个几何物体
It's a triangle mesh, so the vertices are nodes and
因为它是一个三角网格 所以顶点是节点
the edges of the triangles form the edges between the nodes.
而三角形的边 构成了节点间的边
This graph, this large graph of 50,000 nodes is not a planar graph,
这个图 一个有5万个节点的大图 不是一个平面图
but if I make cuts in it, if I separate the faces and duplicate edges,
但是 如果我直接将其剪开 表面会被分开 而边就有重复了
I can turn it into a planar graph just by making these cuts along the black lines.
若沿着这些黑线把它们剪开 我就可以把它转换成一个平面图
And as a planar graph, I can then find a way of embedding it into the plane so
于是 作为一个平面图 接下来我可以找到 一个方式 将其嵌入到一个平面
that the edges don't cross.
使得那些边不会交叉
There's so many nodes and so many edges in this this graph and
这个图中有很多节点和很多边
it's hard to see all of the edges, so trust me that they don't cross.
很难看到所有的边 所以相信我 它们没有相交
Hopefully you'll be working with fewer nodes and edges so
希望你将处理的节点和边较少
that your layouts will be a little more clear than this.
这样你的排布 会比这个稍微清晰一些
So there's a way we can find these embeddings automatically, and
有一个方法使我们能 自动找到这些嵌入
it's called Tutte's Method, and it starts by picking some of your nodes and
它被称为Tutte 方法 一开始 它挑选你的节点中的一部分
defining where they should be in the layout.
并且定义它们在排布中 应放在哪里
So in this case, I'm going to use eight nodes, 12 edges that make a cube,
在这个例子中 我将用组成一个方块的 8个节点和12条边
and I'm going to take these first four nodes,
我将首先选择 这四个节点
and I'm going to find positions for them in for example an SVG Canvass.
我要为它们在这个 示例中的SVG画布上选定位置
I'm going to position node 1 at (0,0), node 2 at (1,0),
我将把节点1放在 (0,0) 节点2放在 (1,0)
node 3 at (0,1), and node 4 at node (1,1).
节点3放在 (0,1) 节点4放在 (1,1)
And then I'm going to try to figure out where do I want to position nodes 5, 6, 7,
然后 我将试图弄清楚 我应把节点5，6，7和8放在哪里
and 8, in order to make a plainer embedding of this graph.
以便生成这个图的一个平面嵌入
This graph is shown in a non planar embedding,
这个图被显示为一个非平面嵌入
because we've got edge crossings.
因为这里有边相互交叉
We want to find out how to make a planar embedding of it.
我们希望找出如何 生成它的一个平面嵌入
So in order to do this automatically for any graph,
为了对任何图都能 自动做到这一点
we're going to need to solve a linear system.
我们将需要 求解一个线性系统
So we'll create a matrix.
所以 我们会建立一个矩阵
In fact, an adjacency matrix,
实际上 是一个相邻矩阵（adjacency matrix）
a special kind of adjacency matrix called a Laplacian matrix.
一种特殊的相邻矩阵 称为拉普拉斯矩阵（Laplacian matrix）
So it's an adjacency matrix which means,
它是一个相邻矩阵 其含义是
I'm going to take one node to another node in case of node 1 is connected to node 2,
在节点1和节点2相连接的情况下 我要将一个节点放到另一个节点那里
so in row one, column two, I'm going to have a non zero entry.
于是在第一行第二列 我会得到一个非零矩阵元素
In this case, the non zero entry is going to be 1 over the degree.
在这个例子中，这个非零元素 将会是1除以其关联度
The node one has degree three,
节点1的关联度是3
it has three edges extending from it, so I'll put a one-third there.
它有三条边从其延展出去 所以我会在这里填入1/3
And so node 1 is connected to nodes 2, 3, and 5,
也就是 节点1和节点2 3 5相连
and so I'll put one-third in columns two, three, and
于是我将把1/3填入第二列 第三列 以及
five, and node one isn't connected to the other nodes.
第五列 节点 1 与其它节点都不相连
So in those columns including node one, in those columns I'll put a zero.
所以 在那些节点所在的列 包括节点 1 的列 我将填入零
The nice thing about the Laplacian form of an adjacency
一个相临矩阵其拉普拉斯形式的美妙之处
matrix is the for node 1 I'm connected to three items.
在于 就节点1来说 我连接到三个节点
My degree is three.
我的关联度是3
The value I'm putting in is one over the degree.
我填入的值是 1 除以关联度
So if I add all of the elements up for row one I get one.
所以 如果我把第一列所有元素 加在一起 我得到的是1
So no we're going to create a special matrix from that Laplacian adjacency
我们要从那个拉布拉斯临接矩阵 建立一个特殊的
matrix.
矩阵。
We'll just call this matrix A.
我们会姑且称这个矩阵为A
First thing I'm going to do is I'm going to take that Laplace matrix, and
我要做的第一件事情是 我要用那个拉普拉斯矩阵
I'm going to zero out all of the rows for the nodes I've already assigned.
我将在所有行中 把已经赋值的节点置成零
So I've already assigned Node 1, 2, 3, and 4 a position.
我已经为节点1 2 3和4设定一个位置
So I'll just zero those out in my adjacency matrix,
我将在我的相临矩阵中 把它们设置为零
subtract the whole thing from the identity matrix.
再将整体减去单位矩阵
The identity matrix just has ones down the diagonal and zeros everyplace else.
单位矩阵是 在对角线元素取值为 1 而其它都为零
That will give me this matrix A that I'm going to solve
这样我就需要求解该矩阵A
in order to find the placements for nodes 5, 6, 7, and 8.
以便为节点5 6 7和8 找到放置的位置
So I need to set up a linear system, and so
所以 我需要建立一个线性系统
we'll set up a linear system for the x coordinates of our nodes, and
我们会为我们的节点 的 x 坐标建立一个线性系统
then we'll set up a separate linear system for the y coordinates.
然后 我们会为 y 坐标 建立一个单独的线性系统
So the linear system we use for the x coordinates looks like this.
我们为 x 坐标所使用 的线性系统看起来像这样
It's my matrix A, and then I've got times x,
这是我的矩阵A 其与 x 相乘
a column vector that's just the x coordinates of my nodes, and
一个列向量 也就是那些节点的 x 坐标
then finally I've got the answer, what the x coordinates actually should be in
最后就是我的答案 即 前四个节点的 x 坐标
the case of the first four nodes and then zeros for the nodes I want to solve.
实际上应该是什么 以及 要求解的那些节点的零值
So this is saying that one times x one, the x coordinate of node one,
就是说 1 乘以 x1 节点 1 的 x 坐标
one time x one and zero times everything else equals zero.
1 乘以 x1 且 0 乘以其它任何项等于 0
Because that what I've assigned.
因为那是我设置过的节点
So here I've got node 0, node 1, nodes 2 and node 3,
所以这里我有了节点 0 节点 1 节点 2 节点 3
these are the x coordinates of node 1, 2, 3, and 4.
这些是节点 1 节点 2 节点 3 和节点 4 的 x 坐标
And so here I've got one, this second row.
这第二行 这里是1
1 times x2 is equal to 1, and the x coordinate of a sine for node two is one.
1 乘以 x2 等于 1 那么 节点 2 的一个设定的 x 坐标是 1
So that's what I put in these first entries
于是 这就是我放入 这个列向量bx
of this bx column vector, and the remaining entries are just zero.
的开始几个元素的值 而剩下的元素都是零
The nice thing here is that if we look at row five,
这里的美妙之处在于 如果我们看一下第五行
row five says that the x coordinate of node 5, x5,
第五行的意思是 节点 5 的 x 坐标 x5
one times x5 minus one-third times x1,
1 乘以 x5 年减去 1/3 乘以 x1
minus one-third times x6,
减去 1/3 乘以 x6
minus one-third times x7, is going to be equal to zero.
减去 1/3 乘以 x7 将会等于零
That's basically setting up a linear equation so
这本质上建立了 一个线性等式 以至于
that wherever I position nodes 6 and 7, they're going to impact node 5.
无论我将节点 6 和 7 放在哪里 它们都将影响到节点 5
Once we do that for rows five, six, seven, and eight corresponding to nodes 5,
一旦我们这样对第5 6 7和 8 行操作 即对应着节点 5
6, 7, and 8, and when we solve this system we'll have positions for
6 7 和 8 那么当我们求解出这个系统的时候 我们能会得到
nodes 5, 6, 7, and 8 that solve that relationship.
能解算出这个关系的节点 5 6 7 和 8 的位置
Do the same thing for the y coordinates.
对于 y 坐标做同样的计算
So now my by column vector is equal to the y coordinates for nodes 1, 2,
现在，我的 by 列向量等于 是我已经摆放的节点 1、2
3 and 4 that I've placed, and then add zeroes for everything else.
3 和 4 的 y 坐标 然后 将其它所有元素都赋值为零
Node 1 has zero for the y coordinate.
节点 1 的 y 坐标是 0
Node 2 has zero for the y coordinate.
节点 2 的 y 坐标是 0
Node 3 has one for the y coordinate, and node 4 has one for the y coordinate,
节点 3 的 y 坐标是 1 节点 4 的 y 坐标是 1
and this is basically saying that y1 = 0, y2 = 0, y3 = 1, y4 = 1.
这实质上是说 y1 = 0, y2 = 0, y3 = 1, y4 = 1
But it's saying that the y coordinate for
但是 对于节点 5 的 y 坐标
node 5 is equal to whatever the y coordinate is for node 5, minus one-third,
无论节点 5 的坐标是多少 它等于负的 1/3乘以
times the y coordinate for node 1, minus one-third the y coordinate for node 6,
节点 1 的 y 坐标 减去 1/3 的节点 6 的 y 坐标
and minus one-third the y coordinate for node 7, and so on for the remaining nodes.
再减去 1/3 节点 7 的 y 坐标 以及如此对剩下的节点推选下去
So I've basically setup these equations for the x system.
于是 我本质上对 x 系统 建立起了这些等式
I said x1 is equal to zero, x2 is equal to one, x3 is equal to zero, and
我说过 x1 等于 0 x2等于 1 x3 等于 0 并且
x4 is equal to one.
x4 等于 1
And then I've set up these equations for the x coordinates of the remaining.
然后 我对剩余节点的 x 坐标 建立起了这些等式
I've set up similar equations for the y coordinate.
对于 y 坐标 我建立了类似的等式
So if I group these together, I basically position x1 and
所以 如果我把这些放在一起 我实际上把节点 1 的 x1 和
y1 at the xy coordinates for node 1 at (0, 0), node 2 at (1,
y1 在 xy 坐标系中放在了(0, 0) 节点 2 放在(1, 0)
0), node 3 at (0, 1), node 4 at (1, 1), and
节点 3 在 (0, 1) 节点 4 在 (1, 1) 并且
I've set up these relationships for remaining coordinates.
我对剩余的坐标已经 建立了这些关系
Now, you might notice something here.
现在 你或许注意到了什么
I'm basically saying that node 5 It's going to be node 1's position
我实际上在说 对于节点 5 它将是节点 1 的位置
plus node 6 position plus node 7 position divided by three.
加上节点 6 的位置 加上节点 7 的位置 其后再除以 3
So basically the position of each node is going to be the average of the position
本质上来说 每一个节点的位置 都将会是其有共享边的
of its neighboring nodes that it shares an edge with, and that's true for
邻居节点位置的平均值 并且这个关系对所有
all the remaining nodes.
剩余节点来说都是正确的
And so we fix the position, we set the position for
所以 我们固定这个位置 我们为我们的节点中
some of our nodes and then the remaining are just
一些节点设定位置 然后剩余的节点就
going to be set to be the average of the nodes that are connected to.
会被设定为与其相连节点 的位置的平均值
And so if I solve that system, if I solve that linear system you can use any
于是 如果我求解了那个系统 如果 我求解了那个线性系统 你可以使用任何
numerical methods you like to solve that matrix problem, you get the solution.
你喜欢的数值方法求解那个 矩阵问题 你就得到了答案
So that node 5 is at (1/3, 1/3).
所以 节点 5 在 (1/3, 1/3)
Node 6 is at (2/3, 1/3).
节点 6 在 (2/3, 1/3)
Node 7 is at (1/3, 2/3), and node 8 is at (2/3, 2/3).
节点 7 在 (1/3, 2/3) 而 节点 8 在 (2/3, 2/3)
And so each of these nodes ends up being at the average, the position of node five
于是 这些节点中的每一个最终 是在平均位置 节点 5 的位置
is equal to the average, the centroid of node one, node six, and node seven.
等于节点 1, 6 和 7 位置的平均 即它们的中心
So I take node 1 plus the position of node 6 plus the position of node 7,
所以 我取节点 1 加上 节点 6的位置 加上节点 7 的位置
divide by three, and I get node 5.
除以 3 我的到节点 5 的位置
So we've solved for these positions of node 5, 6, 7, and
所以 我们求解出 节点5、6、7 以及
8 to find this planar layout of this graph shown here in a non planar
节点 8 的位置 通过求解一个矩阵问题 即为这里显示的一个非平面嵌入的图
embedding by solving a matrix problem.
找到了这个平面表示
You don't have to solve a matrix necessarily to do this.
你并非必须求解一个矩阵 来达到这个目的
You can do the same thing by basically starting with your nodes 1, 2,
你可以通过下面的方法做到同样的事情 实际上从你的节点 1、2
3, 4 in their fixed position, and then for all the remaining nodes,
3、4 的固定位置开始 然后 对所有剩余的节点
you can assign them random positions to begin with and then iteratively,
你可以赋予它们随机位置作为开始 然后再迭代的
replace those node positions with the average of their neighboring nodes.
用它们邻居节点位置的平均 替换那些节点的位置
And if you continually replace every node's position
如果你继续地 用其邻居节点位置
with the average of it's neighboring node's position,
的平均位置 替换每一个节点的位置
those nodes'll work into place where they belong.
那些节点将会逐渐移动到 它们所应该在到位置
And so you can solve this system without setting up a matrix
如此 你可以求解这个系统 但不需要建立一个矩阵
just by constantly doing that iterative procedure
而只是通过持续不断地 进行这一迭代过程
of moving every node to the average of it's neighboring nodes.
移动每一个节点到 其邻居节点到平均位置
So Tutte's method tells us that we can solve a linear system to embed a planar
所以 Tutte的算法告诉我们 我们可以通过求解一个线性系统
graph, but it's not that difficult.
来实现嵌入一个平面图 但这个并不是那么困难
You can do the exact same thing by nailing down
以可以通过确定 你的一些节点到
a few of your nodes into fixed positions.
固定位置 而实现完全相同的事情
And then the rest of the nodes,
然后 剩下的节点
you just replace their position with average of their neighbor's positions,
你只要用它们的邻居节点的平均值来代替
the positions of the neighbors that share an edge with that node.
即那些和那个节点共享一条边的节点
If you keep doing that over and over, those nodes will relax into the exact same
如果你一遍又一遍地持续这样做 那些节点会慢慢到达
position that tutte's method will converge to.
与Tutte算法将收敛到的位置 完全相同的位置
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community